我们为机器人关节设计的控制系统具有很长的血统。
The control systems that we design for the joints of our robot have got a long ancestry.
人类长期以来一直在设计控制系统。这是我们正在进行中的一部分
Human beings have been devising control systems for a long time. It’s been part of our ongoing
利用自然力量的过程。
process to harness the power of nature.
这是大约2000年前HeroofAlexandria发明的装置示意图
Here’s the schematic of a device invented by Hero of Alexandria around 2000 years ago
其目的是在最右边的船只中保持恒定的水位。一个常数
and its purpose was to maintain a constant water level in the right most vessel. A constant
水位导致恒定压力，这对于准确的时间保持很重要
water level result in a constant pressure and that was important for accurate time keeping
用水驱动的时钟。
with a water powered clock.
相关但最近的一个例子是a的系统中的水位控制
A related but more recent instance of this is the control of water level in the system of a
抽水马桶。一个非常简单的机制，如果水位低于理想水平，
flush toilet. A very simple mechanism, if the water level is less than the desired level,
如果水位大于或等于所需水量，则水流入水箱
water flows into the tank and if the water level is greater than or equal to the desired
然后它停止流入油箱。
level then it stops flowing into the tank.
这是一项在利用风力发电方面非常重要的创新。如果主刀片
Here’s an innovation that was important in harnessing wind power. If the main blades
没有直接指向风，然后一些风将通过小风扇
are not pointing directly into the wind then some wind will pass through the small fan
尾巴。这将导致风车的整个顶部旋转，因此它指向
tail. And that will cause the whole top of the windmill to rotate so it points
主叶片直接进风。
the main blades directly into the wind.
一个非常重要的发明，也许是在工业革命的基础上，是离心的
A really important invention, perhaps under pinned the industrial revolution, is the centrifugal
州长发明或至少由詹姆斯瓦特完善。如果蒸汽机正在运转
governor invented or at least perfected by James Watt. If the steam engine is running
离心调速器过快会减少进入发动机的蒸汽量。
too fast then the centrifugal governor reduces the amount of steam going into the engine.
同样，如果发动机运转得太慢，它会让更多的蒸汽进入发动机
And similarly if the engine is going too slowly it allows more steam into the engine and it
即使发动机上的负载可能变化，也允许发动机以恒定速度运转。
allows the engine to run at constant speed even though the load on the engine may be varying.
花了很长时间才提出一般的控制理论和很多非常聪明的理论
It took a long time to come up with a general theory of control and a lot of very smart
人们在很长一段时间内为此做出了贡献。哈拉尔德布莱克，在这里显示
people contributed to this over a long period of time. Harald Black, shown here in the
中间，真正形式化负反馈理论，即你减去输出
middle, really formalized the theory of negative feedback and that is you subtract the output
从所需输入到系统的系统。这项技术获得了Black的专利
of the system from the desired input to the system. This technique was patented by Black
改善长途电话网络中使用的放大器的性能。
to improve the performance of amplifiers used in long distance telephone networks.
随着小额数字产品的推出，控制方面的一项重大创新也随之而来
A really big innovation in control came with the introduction of affordable small digital
计算机，也许是第一个也许是最着名的例子之一
computers and perhaps one of the first and perhaps best known examples of this was the
小型数字计算机，用于将阿波罗宇宙飞船导航到月球并引导
small digital computer that was built to navigate Apollo spacecraft to the moon and to guide
月球模块从轨道上到月球表面。
the lunar module from orbit onto the moon’s surface.
这里再次是显示典型机器人关节控制系统的组件的图表
Here again is the diagram that shows the components of a typical robot joint control system and
我们在这里看到负反馈回路，其中我们有所需的位置和反馈
we see here the negative feedback loop where we have the desired position and also feedback
实际位置
of the actual position.
我们还没有谈到的系统的一部分是位置传感器。最普遍的
One part of the system that we haven’t yet talked about is the position sensor. The most common
用于感测电模型的角度的技术曾被称为增量编码器。
technique for sensing the angle of an electric model is once called an incremental encoder.
在这里，我们可以看到增量编码器的一些示例，通常还有增量编码器
Here we can see some examples of incremental encoders and typically the incremental encoder
安装在电动机总成的一端。
is fitted to one end of the motor assembly.
所以现在你买了一个集成电机组件，它是一个电动机。它的
So these days you buy an integrated motor assembly it’s an electric motor. It’s
有一个齿轮箱，它有一个编码器，提供信号告诉你电机轴的角度。
got a gear box and it’s got an encoder which provides signals to tell you the angle of the motor shaft.
增量编码器的原理非常简单。我们有一个开槽磁盘
The principle of an incremental encoder is pretty simple. We have a slotted disk on the
电机轴和一对LED通过插槽照射光线，并由一对拾取
motor shaft and a pair of LEDs shine light through the slots and that are picked up by a pair
照片探测器。这两个LED位于半槽之间，因此输出信号来自
of photo detectors. The two LEDs are positioned a half slot apart, so the output signals from
当电机顺时针旋转时，探测器看起来像这样
the detectors looks something like this when the motor is spinning in the clockwise direction
当电机逆时针旋转时，它看起来像这样。
and it looks something like this when the motor is spinning in the counter clockwise direction.
为了确定电机角度，我们需要做的就是对脉冲进行计数，但它是
In order to determine the motor angle all we need to do is to count the pulses but it’s
重要的是要知道我们是在向上还是向下计数，这取决于旋转方向。
important to know whether we’re counting up or down and that depends on the direction of rotation.
旋转方向实际上很容易确定。我们看看上升的边缘
The direction of rotation is actually very easy to determine. We look at the rising edge
在A信号中，我们测量B信号的值。如果B信号为零
of the A signal and we measure the value of the B signal. If the B signal is zero on the
然后我们正在顺时针移动，如果B信号在上升沿是1
rising edge then we’re moving clockwise and if the B signal is one on the rising edge
然后电机逆时针旋转。
then the motor is rotating in the counter clockwise direction.
增量编码器简单而便宜。它们为我们提供了旋转方向
Incremental encoders are simple and cheap. They give us the direction of rotation and
还有来自每秒脉冲数的转速。如果我们算数
also the rotational speed that comes from the number of pulses per second. If we count
由于输出信号，脉冲我们可以确定电机轴的角位置
the pulses we can determine the angular position of the motor shaft because the output signals
光电探测器是二进制的，很容易与廉价的微控制器接口。
of the photo detectors are binary, very easy to interface to a cheap micro controller.
机器人关节控制系统的另一个重要组成部分是微控制器。现代
Another important component in the robot joint control system is the micro controller. Modern
微控制器将非常多的功能集成到一个非常小的包中。他们有类似的
micro controllers pack an awful lot of functionality into a very small package. They have analogue
输入和输出，数字输入和输出，也许他们有串口。
input and output, digital input and output, perhaps they've got serial ports.
在内部，它们具有大量计数器和定时器以及带调制发生器的脉冲
Internally they have a large number of counters and timers and pulse with modulation generators
除了带有RAM的小型计算机，有时还有非易失性存储器。他们是
in addition to a small computer with RAM and sometimes non-volatile memory as well. They’re
易于与网络连接到键盘和显示器;今天非常非常多才多艺
easy to interface to a network to a keyboard and a display; very, very versatile and today
非常非常低成本的设备。
very, very low cost devices.
最后机器人关节控制器看起来像这样。我们有联合控制器本身
Finally the robot joint controller looks something like this. We have the joint controller itself
这是一种在嵌入式微处理器内的联合控制器中运行的算法。
which is an algorithm running in the joint controller inside an embedded micro processor.
通常，它将脉冲宽度调制信号输出到电机驱动器，即H
Typically it outputs a pulse-width-modulated signal to the motor drive, which is this H
驱动执行器的桥接电路，小型电动机。有一个变速箱
bridge circuit that drives the actuator, a small electric motor. There is a gearbox which
将电动机连接到机器人关节，我们使用变速箱相对放大
connects the electric motor to the robot joint and we use a gearbox to amplify the relatively
电动机的低扭矩到移动所需的较大扭矩
low torque from the electric motor to the larger torque which is needed to move the
机器人的链接。
link of the robot.
我们使用增量编码器来测量电机轴的位置，我们可以配对
We use an incremental encoder to measure the position of the motor shaft and we can pair
具有所需位置的我们希望关节进入关节
that with the desired position that we want the joint to have that goes into the joint
控制器和循环关闭。
controller and the loop is closed.
我们可以创建该机器人关节控制器系统的动态模型。关键部分
We can create a dynamic model of that robot joint controller system. A critical part of
这是求和点。这是我们输入机器人所需位置的地方
this is the summing junction. This is where we input the desired position of the robot
联合，我们从实际位置减去。
joint and we subtract from that actual position.
这是负反馈系统的本质，期望的位置减去实际
This is the essence of a negative feedback system, the desired position minus the actual
位置。结果是位置错误，并进入控制律。
position. The result of that is the error in position and that goes into a control law.
控制律的输出是一个发送给电机驱动器并应用的信号
The output of the control law is a signal that goes to the motor driver and applies
一些任意增益我称之为KD并产生一个电流应用于传递函数
some arbitrary gain I call it KD and generates a current is applied to the transfer function
对于执行器，这里显示。
for the actuator, which is shown here.
其结果是电机的位置。我们有一个传感器，可以测量位置
The result of which is position of the motor. We have a sensor, which measures the position
电动机和我们的模型，增益为1，这是信号，减去
of the motor and our model that by a gain of one and this is the signal, which is subtracted
从理想的位置。
from the desired position.